

Todd Rings Manager || Educator

Manager || Educator Self-Taught Programmer



Key Achievements

Utilized modern technologies to help educate English learners of all ages.

Trained, managed and evaluated 20 teachers to create dynamic lesson plans, educational progress examinations and instructive lessons to children aged 5 to 13.

Created, edited and managed an English-language newspaper written by students and distributed throughout an entire elementary school for 3 years.

Led training and implementation of a co-teaching system that allowed for two teachers to teach properly planned material in-tandem for immersive English lessons in various subjects alongside Korean managerial counterpart.

Professional Experience

Manager and Head Teacher Trainer

Calm Island, Co., Ltd., Seoul, South Korea, August 2017-Dec 2017 Hired as a manager for the Professional Development Team at a global ESL E-learning company creating the Badanamu English educational products targeting preschool and kindergarden children.

Job duties include:

- Managed teachers at various Badanamu English centers.
- Maintained and Updated company newsletter.
- Product trainer for all new employees.
- Communicated directly with various Badanamu English franchise managers.
- Conducted demo classes for new instructors.

Manager and Head Native English Teacher

Hongik University Elementary School, Seoul, South Korea, 2010-2017 Joined as a Native English Teacher and was promoted to a management level as Head Native English Teacher in 2012, after two years at a private elementary school.

Job duties included:

- Creation of educational lesson plans that were shared among various English teachers.
- Creation of supplementary educational materials that were shared among various English teachers.
- Managed, trained and evaluation of Native and Korean English teachers.
- Creation of Hongik Post, an after-school English Newspaper and Magazine
 Class
- Implementation of a co-teaching system to help English teachers interact more with students.

Native English Teacher

Carrot Global, Outsourced Teacher, 2017-Present YBM, Outsourced Teacher, 2018 BCM, Outsourced Teacher, 2018 YJ Sisa, Outsourced Teacher 2018 Yeomri Elementary School, 2017 Eunseok Elementary School, 2014-2015 Seoul Mirae Elementary School, 2008-2010 Kumho Tire, 2008 TNL School, Head Teacher, 2007-2008 Wonderland English Academy, 2005-2007

Programming Skills

Object-Oriented Programming JavaScript

• ECMAScript 6 (ES6)

trejiiten

• ECMAScript 5 (ES5)

JavaScript Frameworks

- React JS
- jQuery
- Express js
- Meteor js

node.js

PHP

HTML 5

CSS 3

Microsoft Office

Adobe InDesign

Other Skills

School Newspaper Editor School Event Coordinator Product Trainer Teacher Trainer Detailed Lesson Planning Written, Listening, Oral Test Creation Detailed Teacher Evaluation With Constructive Feedback Level Testing Client-Centered Lesson Creation

Education

Supplementary Material

Creation And Implementation

Bachelors of Business Administration in Marketing with an International Emphasis Texas Christian University, Fort Worth, Texas

Volunteering Experience

Korean Scouting Association

Recognized Scout Leader, 2012-2014 Mapo Scouts Association Educational Instructor, 2015-2017

First native English speaking Scout Leader and native English speaking education instructor for the Mapo Scouts Association.

Duties Included:

- Teaching all Korean Cub Scouting content in English.
- Teaching safety and how scouting knots can assist in rescue operations.
- Chaperone Scout groups on monthly Scouting trips.
- Lead opening and closing ceremonies in English and Korean